<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>vim abozanona</title>
  
  
  <link href="https://abozanona.me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://abozanona.me/"/>
  <updated>2024-03-24T15:42:14.712Z</updated>
  <id>https://abozanona.me/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Abozanona</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Rendering Spine animation with PIXI.JS</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/integrating-spine-with-pixi-js/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/integrating-spine-with-pixi-js/</id>
    <published>2024-03-18T22:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-03-24T15:42:14.712Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Spine 2D, a powerful tool for creating captivating animations, offers immense potential for web-based projects. However, integrating Spine animations seamlessly into web applications isn’t always straightforward, as I discovered during my journey with <a href="https://github.com/abozanona/petmety">Petmety</a>, an exciting Chrome extension project aimed at bringing virtual pets to screens everywhere.</p><span id="more"></span><p>During the development of Petmety, I encountered a perplexing issue while attempting to render Spine animations using the default <a href="https://en.esotericsoftware.com/spine-player">JavaScript web player</a> provided by Spine. Instead of fluid movements, certain animations, like a character jump, exhibited unexpected behavior. Rather than smoothly moving up and down, the sprite would distort, scaling down before performing the action and then returning to its original size.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/integrating-spine-with-pixi-js/petmety-before.gif"></p><p>I delved into potential solutions, turning to PIXI’s documentation for guidance. There, I discovered references to external libraries that promised to address rendering issues. My research led me to explore various JavaScript libraries compatible with Spine animations. Among them, <a href="https://pixijs.com/">PIXI.js</a> emerged as the standout choice. Renowned for its versatility and active development community, PIXI.js seemed tailor-made for the task.</p><p>However, my journey was far from over. PIXI.js presented its own set of challenges, particularly concerning its multitude of versions and broken <a href="https://pixijs.io/examples-v7/#/plugin-spine/spineboy-pro">online examples</a>. With significant disparities between versions 6, 7, and 8, finding relevant and functional examples proved arduous. Despite the official documentation’s wealth of resources, many examples failed to execute properly, complicating my efforts to implement Spine animations seamlessly.</p><p>I started searching documentation and GitHub issues for insights. After numerous rounds of trial and error, I managed to run the Spineboy demo locally using PIXI.js libraries from their content delivery network (CDN). While this marked a significant milestone, it fell short of my ultimate goal due to the project’s specific requirements.</p><p>As I aimed to integrate Spine animations into a Chrome extension using Manifest V3, I encountered additional hurdles. Navigating npm package dependencies and ensuring compatibility with an “eval-safe” environment posed new challenges. Fortunately, PIXI.js offered a lifeline with its <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@pixi/unsafe-eval">unsafe-eval</a> package, enabling functionality within such constrained environments.</p><p>After meticulously integrating packages, code, and assets while adhering to Manifest <a href="https://developer.chrome.com/docs/extensions/develop/migrate/improve-security">V3’s security constraints</a>, victory was finally within reach. However, one last obstacle remained: animations refusing to render; no exception was showing in the console anymore, but also still nothing is rendered on the screen.</p><p>Through diligent research, I uncovered the solution—a crucial adjustment to the project’s TypeScript configuration, compiling using ES6 modules. This is how the animation looks like after the fix.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/integrating-spine-with-pixi-js/petmety-after.gif"></p><p>In my endeavor to render Spine 2D animations within web environments, the development journey with Petmety has been characterized by a series of formidable challenges and notable achievements. From confronting perplexing rendering anomalies to navigating intricate disparities among PIXI.js versions and adhering to stringent manifest specifications, each hurdle has served as a crucible for personal and professional growth.</p><p>For those curious to explore the culmination of my efforts, I cordially invite you to delve into the Petmety project repository. Therein lies a firsthand depiction of the seamless integration of Spine animations into a Chrome extension.</p><p>For those intrigued by the technical intricacies of the solution implemented, I encourage you to follow this link to delve into the code detailing the fix I orchestrated: <a href="https://github.com/abozanona/petmety/commit/748246c15145f6d6a8456c07806943de43d7673b">Petmety GitHub Commit</a>. There, you’ll find a comprehensive breakdown of the adjustments made to rectify the rendering issues encountered, providing valuable insights into the process of integrating Spine 2D animations into web environments with finesse and precision.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spine 2D, a powerful tool for creating captivating animations, offers immense potential for web-based projects. However, integrating Spine animations seamlessly into web applications isn’t always straightforward, as I discovered during my journey with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/abozanona/petmety&quot;&gt;Petmety&lt;/a&gt;, an exciting Chrome extension project aimed at bringing virtual pets to screens everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="technical" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/technical/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Occupation&#39;s settlements in the Westbank</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/settelments-in-the-westbank/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/settelments-in-the-westbank/</id>
    <published>2024-01-18T22:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-01-30T20:41:30.713Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amer Abu Hujla is a Palestinian farmer living in a village called Deir Istiya in the West Bank. One day, he and his family went to pick their olive trees in their land. To their surprise, they found a large group of settlers digging a pit and constructing a swimming pool, surrounded by many seats.</p><span id="more"></span><iframe height="250" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FRadioBaladnaNewsNetwork%2Fvideos%2F3408356359240801%2F" style="width:100%;"></iframe><p>Amer quickly called his relatives and neighbors, and together they managed to drive the settlers away and fill the pit they had dug. Shortly after, Amer returned to his land, only to be accused by the settlers who complained about him. Consequently, Amer was taken to the Ofer Prison, where he remained imprisoned for an extended period, only gaining release after paying a hefty fine.</p><p>Amer is considered quite lucky when compared to what happened to Abdullah Yasin from the village of Yasuf. Abdullah, anticipating trouble, decided to fence off his land before the settlers could come and damage it. One day, he arrived to find not only had the settlers demolished his fence, but they had also uprooted and destroyed the olive trees that took years of care and hard work to cultivate.</p><p>Amer and Abdullah are considered lucky compared to what happened to Mithqal Rayan from the village of Qarawat Bani Hasan. Just a few months ago, settlers shot and killed him while he was trying to defend his land.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.aa.com.tr/ar/%D8%A5%D8%B3%D8%B1%D8%A7%D8%A6%D9%8A%D9%84/%D9%85%D9%82%D8%AA%D9%84-%D9%81%D9%84%D8%B3%D8%B7%D9%8A%D9%86%D9%8A-%D8%A8%D8%B1%D8%B5%D8%A7%D8%B5-%D9%85%D8%B3%D8%AA%D9%88%D8%B7%D9%86-%D8%A5%D8%B3%D8%B1%D8%A7%D8%A6%D9%8A%D9%84%D9%8A-%D8%A8%D8%A7%D9%84%D8%B6%D9%81%D8%A9-/2816288#">source: A Palestinian was killed by Israeli settler gunfire in the West Bank</a></li></ul><p>Similarly, Fawzi, another resident, faced a tragic fate when Israeli soldiers fired at him and killed him near Nablus. The way he was shot represents the occupation army command’s instructions to soldiers in the field to always place a bullet in the house of fire, that is, in a permanent position to fire ammunition. This is also known as the “shoot first, ask later” policy which means that the Israeli soldier has the right to pull the trigger whenever He sensed danger, and wanted to kill without hesitation, without batting an eyelid, and to ask questions later. This is the same policy that led to the killing of three Israeli hostages in the last war in Gaza.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/7/22/palestinians-call-for-probe-into-israeli-killing-of-teenager">source: Palestinians call for probe into Israeli killing of teenager</a></li><li><a href="https://www.trtworld.com/magazine/how-israels-shoot-first-ask-later-policy-turns-against-its-own-citizens-16302493">source: How Israel’s ‘shoot first, ask later’ policy turns against its own citizens</a></li></ul><p>Since the beginning of the current war on Gaza, Israel has consistently employed global media outlets to convey a narrative that emphasizes their stance. They assert that their war is not against the Palestinian people as a whole; rather, they claim to have an issue solely with Hamas. According to their narrative, without Hamas, Palestinians would live in peace and prosperity, and Israel would have no problem with them. This propaganda aims to downplay the broader complexities of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict and present a simplified version that aligns with their perspective.</p><p>What is happening in the West Bank mirrors some aspects of the war on Gaza, but at a slower pace. The current government under Netanyahu represents the most right-wing and extremist administration in Israel’s history. The influence of settlers is so significant that statements from some officials in this government even provoke officials within the United States government. The situation in the West Bank, despite being distinct from Gaza, is characterized by ongoing tensions and challenges, contributing to the overall complexity of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.</p><p>Multiple times in the past year, and even before the current conflict, American officials criticized statements made by individuals such as Itamar Ben Gvir and Zviel Smotrich, among others. What sets these two apart is that they are settlers residing in the West Bank and simultaneously hold ministerial positions in the Israeli government. This dual role raises legal and ethical questions, as they are ministers in a government while living outside its recognized borders. It’s akin to imagining a scenario where the Italian Minister of Foreign Affairs resides in Greece. The intertwining of settlement residency and governmental roles has created a complex situation, prompting scrutiny and concerns.</p><p>Looking back to the period before the June 1967 Six-Day War, despite Israel’s control over most of historical Palestine, there were voices within Israel itself expressing dissatisfaction. Even as Israel dominated a significant portion of Palestinian territories, there was a movement within Israeli society, led by figures such as Rabbi Yehuda Kook, that considered it a failure. Rabbi Kook criticized the founders of the Israeli state, declaring, “You abandoned Judea and Samaria,” referring to the biblical names for the West Bank. At that time, the West Bank was part of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan after the 1948 Arab-Israeli War. However, following the Arab armies’ defeat in the 1967 War, Israel occupied the West Bank, Gaza Strip, Sinai Peninsula, and the Golan Heights.</p><ul><li><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Decolonization_-_World_In_1945_en.svg">Palestine map accourding to UN: Decolonization - World In 1945</a></li><li><a href="https://digitallibrary.un.org/record/710999">Palestine map accourding to UN: The world in 1945</a></li><li><a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/11/27/palestine-and-israel-brief-history-maps-and-charts">source: Israel-Palestine conflict: A brief history in maps and charts</a></li></ul><p>For Rabbi Kook’s disciples, the occupation of the West Bank symbolized a divine sign, encouraging them to settle in and claim the land. This perspective laid the groundwork for the settlement movement, which later became a contentious issue in the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.</p><p>During Levi Eshkol’s tenure as the Prime Minister of Israel, when Israeli law viewed the West Bank as foreign territory that their military had seized, the legal advisor, Theodor Meron, responded by sending a confidential message to the Prime Minister, stating that according to the law, they had no right to settle in the land. He emphasized that the territory was not theirs; it was occupied, and this contradicted the Geneva Conventions, to which Israel was a signatory.</p><p>Meron made it clear that, according to international law, it was impermissible for an occupying state to transfer its civilian population to the territories it had occupied. Despite this legal advice, when the Israeli government learned that international law prohibited such actions, they went ahead with the establishment of settlements. They chose to disregard international law and agreements. Confronted with the religious extremists associated with Rabbi Kook, the government essentially told them to build seletments wherever they wanted in the westbank, not adhering to international legal standards.</p><p>The Israeli settlement in the West Bank did not solely emerge from religious motivations; there were also strategic and security considerations, particularly during the late 1960s. According to Israeli officials of that time, the primary purpose of the settlements was military and security-oriented.</p><p>During a television interview, Yigal Allon, who was the Deputy Prime Minister of Israel at the time, was asked about the justifications for the settlements. He responded that there was no need for historical or ethical justifications; it was purely a strategic defense policy. Allon explained that when they establish a settlement in a particular location, it automatically becomes part of their defense system. The interviewer pressed him, questioning whether the world would remain silent while Israel pursued settlement policies that violated international laws. Allon confidently asserted that the world could indeed stand idly by, accepting Israel’s actions.</p><p>The mentioned plan by Yigal Allon indeed played a crucial role in shaping Israeli territorial control, especially after the 1967 Six-Day War. At that time, Yigal Allon held the position of Minister of Labor and later became Deputy Prime Minister. His plan involved establishing a security barrier along the West Bank, running parallel to the Jordan River, encompassing the Jordan Valley, which Israel later seized.</p><p>The Jordan Valley, known as the “Al-Ghawar,” became a strategic target for Israel due to both economic and security reasons. Economically, it served as the West Bank’s breadbasket, boasting fertile land and a climate conducive to year-round agriculture. Additionally, security considerations played a significant role, as Palestinian factions were concentrated in Jordan during the late 1960s. Israel sought to control the Jordan Valley to diminish the influence and operations of Palestinian guerrilla groups that had operated from Jordan.</p><p>The move to clear the Jordan Valley and designate it as a closed military zone aimed at both economic and security objectives. Economically, Israel wanted to control the region’s resources, while security-wise, the plan aimed to cut off Palestinian factions from the Jordanian side. This strategy of creating physical separations between territories and controlling key areas has been a recurring theme in Israeli policy, as demonstrated in current events, such as the pursuit of strategic control over the Philadelphia Corridor to separate Gaza from Egypt.</p><p>After securing control over the Jordan Valley, Israel turned its attention to creating a second belt of settlements along the Green Line in the western part of the West Bank. The Green Line was established as a demarcation line between Israel and Jordan after the armistice following the 1948 Arab-Israeli War. The purpose of this belt of settlements was similar to that of the Jordan Valley – to hinder communication between the West Bank, Jerusalem, and the areas occupied by Israel in 1948.</p><p>This settlement belt, along with the Jordan Valley, created a strategic barrier, restricting connectivity and movement between different Palestinian territories. Additionally, there is a settlement axis known as Ariel or Trans-Samaria. It essentially forms a line of settlements starting west of the Green Line and diverges within the West Bank until reaching the settlements in the eastern part of the Jordan Valley. This configuration encircles the West Bank, effectively dividing it into two halves.</p><p>In essence, these settlement strategies were aimed at both controlling key economic and agricultural areas and creating barriers to the geographic and social unity of Palestinian territories, following a pattern that aligns with historical Israeli policies in the region.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/11/6/who-are-israeli-settlers-and-why-do-they-live-on-palestinian-lands">more details: Who are Israeli settlers, and why do they live on Palestinian lands?</a></li></ul><p>Where did they secure the lands on which they’re building these houses in general? When Israel initially occupied the West Bank, it categorized the lands into three sections:</p><ol><li><p>Public State Lands:<br>Israel claimed them as state property, asserting its control over them, despite this conflicting with international law.</p></li><li><p>Lands of Palestinians who fled after the 1967 war:<br>Israel pondered how to address the legal aspect, and being keen on legal formalities, they enacted the “Absentee Property Law” in 1967. This law facilitated Israel’s acquisition of lands belonging to Palestinians who were absent due to the 1967 war. In summary, Israel placed its hands on the majority of West Bank lands through this section, leaving only the third section – private lands owned by Palestinians still residing in the West Bank. However, this section has not been fully executed by Israel. </p></li><li><p>Pretext of public interest<br>It’s worth noting that if you own land with documented proof in your name, the government can expropriate it under the pretext of public interest, claiming it serves public benefit. For example, if your land is in the path of a planned separation barrier, they might leave it or take it based on the perceived greater public interest. The situation became more challenging for Palestinians witnessing the substantial funds successive Israeli governments allocate to build settlements, develop, and pamper them, while Palestinian areas suffer complete neglect. This has led to frustration, accusation, and a divide among Palestinians.</p></li></ol><p>Even after participating in the Oslo Accords in 1993, which granted the Palestinian Authority the ability to administer major population centers in the West Bank, the situation did not witness significant development. About 60% of the West Bank’s area, particularly outside major cities, continued to be under direct Israeli occupation, and the promise of settlement cessation, as per the Oslo Accords, was short-lived, with settlements resuming and expanding.</p><p>On the day of the Oslo Accords signing, the number of settlers in the West Bank was around 268,000. Today, the number has increased to approximately 750,000 settlers, nearly tripling in this period. During this time, Israeli officials were publicly stating that settlement activities were frozen or, at the very least, claiming that they were not actively supporting them. However, in reality, government support for settlement construction in the West Bank did not stop, even during the administrations of Rabin, Peres, and Barak, who were considered more moderate. The distinction was that those classified as moderates were supporting settlement activities discreetly, under the table. In contrast, the extremists, such as Sharon and Netanyahu, openly declared their support for settlement construction in the West Bank, showing little concern for international resolutions or U.S. criticisms.</p><p>A clear example that illustrates the lack of distinction between moderate and extremist Israeli governments is the phenomenon of settlement outposts. An Israeli settler, without formal approval, might decide to set up a tent or bring a caravan to an area of interest in the Palestinian territories. This can be considered a mini-settlement, and it reflects the on-the-ground reality. The concept was initiated by Ariel Sharon when he was the Minister of Infrastructure in 1996. He encouraged settlers to find strategic locations in hills and elevated areas, and settle there. These settlement outposts began to emerge in 1996, right after the Oslo Accords, and have continued to grow under various Israeli governments, whether right-wing or left-wing.</p><p>The Israeli government officially denies recognizing these outposts as authorized settlements. However, in practice, successive Israeli governments have provided them with essential services such as electricity, water, and education. The settlers who strategically plan, build, and develop these outposts receive support from the Israeli government, despite the government’s formal denial of their legitimacy. These outposts are treated as if they were part of Israel, even though they are located in the West Bank. The numbers of both settlement outposts and their population have increased, and their areas have expanded since the Oslo Accords.</p><ul><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Israeli_outpost">source: Wikipedia - Israeli outpost</a></li></ul><p>The largest settlement in the West Bank is considered Ma’ale Adumim, and its establishment began in 1994 during Rabin’s government, following the signing of the Oslo Accords II. As for the second-largest Israeli settlement, it is Betar Illit, with a population of approximately 70,000 people. Looking back to the time when the peace agreements began, around 30 years ago, the population of Betar Illit did not exceed 5,000 during the 30 years after the settlement freeze; its population increased 14 times. This implies that if there hadn’t been a freeze on construction during that period, the increase would have been even greater.</p><p>The question that arises is: What drives the government of the occupying state to support the construction of settlements in the West Bank despite international opposition? This is attributed to the desire to assert control over the land, achieve strategic and political goals, and send strong messages to the Palestinians and the international community, despite widespread reservations and objection to this policy.</p><p>The reality, when you look at the map and observe the distribution of settlements across the West Bank, without being a military or strategic analyst, it becomes evident that the goal is to eliminate any hope of establishing a viable Palestinian state able to stand on its own and sustain life. The Palestinian territories in the West Bank have transformed or have been transformed into scattered islands, distant from each other, lacking any geographical or population connectivity. Broad bypass roads, restricted to Israelis, sever these areas, making communication between them difficult.</p><p>As the writer and Palestinian legal expert Raif Fazaa states, the occupied Palestinian territories in the West Bank have become simultaneously closer and farther inside and outside Israel. If we see Gaza as a type of violence, bombing, and massacres, the West Bank experiences a different kind of violence with various urban and organizational schemes aiming to prevent Palestinians from living comfortably. Examples include the construction of the apartheid wall, which cuts through Palestinian lands, and the approximately 108 fixed military checkpoints in the West Bank that impede and complicate the lives of Palestinians.</p><p>The 770-meter-long apartheid wall, along with the military checkpoints, create a fragmented and restricted living environment for Palestinians, disrupting their daily lives and causing considerable suffering. The situation worsened after October 7; the number of settlers increased, and they became more violent, attacking Palestinian homes more aggressively. In the past three months alone, the number of Palestinian martyrs reached 317, reflecting the escalation of violence.</p><p>This suffering is exacerbated by the support and encouragement of high-ranking Israeli officials. Minister Uri Ariel announced the distribution of 4,000 weapons to settlers, indicating the alarming situation. Despite all these challenges, the Palestinian struggle continues in the face of Israeli policies and actions.</p><p>Many intellectuals and certain Israeli political currents argue that the danger of annexing lands in the West Bank, building settlements, and venturing into its depths lies in either eliminating the Jewish character of the state or jeopardizing the establishment of a Palestinian state. They say that canceling the project of establishing a Palestinian state and annexing the West Bank to Israel will lead to one of two outcomes.</p><p>Firstly, it could mean the elimination of the Jewish character of the state, as the population of Palestinians in the West Bank, surpassing 3 million, would become the majority on the greater land of Israel from the sea to the river, encompassing the historic Palestinian territories. Since the inception of Zionist presence in the occupied lands, they have always expressed reluctance to become a minority on this land. They argue that they are not ready to be a minority in a state where Arabs constitute the majority. If they are not prepared for this, there is a second possibility.</p><p>Secondly, it may result in the preservation of a Jewish state of Israel, but it would require openly adopting an apartheid system—a state of racial segregation. In this scenario, there would be laws for Arabs and laws for Jews. Palestinians would live a life of poverty, marginalization, and oppression. The Israeli, who is sitting on the land he confiscated, enjoys a better life. This situation would threaten the security and stability of the occupying state, creating internal disturbances, security challenges, and international pressures over time. It could lead to problems similar to the pressures that South Africa faced under the apartheid regime, ultimately causing its collapse.</p><br/><p>Article content is a translation for the video “How do the people of the West Bank live? Is it really not occupied?”</p><iframe height="250" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C_v-26UQhpc" style="width:100%;"></iframe>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Amer Abu Hujla is a Palestinian farmer living in a village called Deir Istiya in the West Bank. One day, he and his family went to pick their olive trees in their land. To their surprise, they found a large group of settlers digging a pit and constructing a swimming pool, surrounded by many seats.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="diary" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/diary/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>New Year&#39;s Eve in Gaza Amidst Shattered Lives</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/new-year-in-gaza/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/new-year-in-gaza/</id>
    <published>2024-01-01T22:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-01-30T22:09:04.711Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe height="250" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PwHr_vmW-oo" style="width:100%;"></iframe><span id="more"></span><link rel="stylesheet" href="https://demos.ramon.codes/zuck.js/dist/skins/snapgram.css"><link rel="stylesheet" href="https://demos.ramon.codes/zuck.js/dist/zuck.min.css"><style>.tip.link {pointer-events: none;} #zuck-modal.with-effects{position: fixed !important;}</style><div id="stories" class="storiesWrapper"></div><script>    getAvatar = (id) => "https://api.multiavatar.com/avatar-" + id + ".png"    var currentSkin = {      avatars: true,      list: false,      autoFullScreen: false,      cubeEffect: true,      paginationArrows: false    };    var zuckScript      = document.createElement('script');    zuckScript.src      = "https://demos.ramon.codes/zuck.js/dist/zuck.min.js";    zuckScript.async    = false;     document.body.appendChild(zuckScript);         zuckScript.addEventListener('load', () => {        fetch("/assets/stories.json").then(res => res.json()).then(res => {            let storiesList = [];            for(el of res) {                if(el.count) {                    storiesList.push(...Array(el.count).fill(el).map((st, indx) => ({...st, url: st.url + "&index="+indx})))                } else {                    storiesList.push(el);                }            }            groupArray = storiesList.reduce((group, entry) => {                const time = new Date(entry.time).toISOString().split('T')[0];                    group[time] = group[time] ?? [];                    group[time].push(entry);                    return group;                }, {});            groupArray = Object.entries(groupArray).map(el =>  {                    return Zuck.buildTimelineItem(                        el[0],                         getAvatar(el[0]),                        el[0],                        "",                        new Date(el[1][0]).getTime() / 1000,                        el[1].map(story => ([                            story.time, story.type, 10, story.url, false, story.description?'#!':false, story.description, false, new Date(story.time).getTime() / 1000                        ]))                    )                })            let reversedArray = groupArray.reverse();            var stories = new Zuck('stories', {                backNative: true,                previousTap: true,                skin: currentSkin['name'],                autoFullScreen: currentSkin.autoFullScreen,                avatars: currentSkin.avatars,                paginationArrows: currentSkin.paginationArrows,                list: currentSkin.list,                cubeEffect: currentSkin.cubeEffect,                localStorage: true,                stories: reversedArray            }            )        });    });</script><p>In whose words would i write this? Who is more deserving to speak in the wake of the resistance? The faceless bunch that chose to free us all, But have they even a choice?</p><p>They say you should never meet your heroes, those who have been glorified by the screen and  don’t extend depth beyond the surface…but my heroes are real, they are so real i see them everyday and on every platform, and if you guide your steps away from the pit of lies you are tossed in everyday, you would see them too. In your father, a man who has lost his beloved wife and all the blessings she gave him in nine children, hugs the bricks of his fallen home screaming in the dust “who do i hug now!”</p><p>In your mom, a force of a woman carrying the remains of her two babies in plastic bags to give them a proper barial, a force so fierce that she hugs her daughter with missing limps and open flesh laying on the hospital bed for the last time. </p><p>But now, it’s been a couple of cold hours and you can no longer see your mom at all, a deep heavy void sets inside of you as you start to gather the pieces one by one, “Is this her arm? No this is my sister’s ring…is my sister gone too? But I just saw her with…”</p><p>Yes she is gone too, so is your brother, his wife and son, his favorite toys are among the rubble of what once used to be your childhood neighborhood, years and years of memories erased. “Hey there is a batman t-shirt peeking from under these stones maybe this kid is still alive”, was that his favorite super hero too? Little did he know that these big companies’ funds would be the end of him, and for years to come we would say that our favorite super hero was you. When you saw your wife tearfully holding a positive pregnancy test, did you also see her 8 months pregnant getting run over by an IOF truck to death? What was her fault? </p><p>Ah yes, the most recurring question “what was their fault?” </p><p>The truth is, and the truth is beyond negotiable after 80 days of horror on earth, that they didn’t stand a chance in the face of this vicious world, a world where power consumes, power devours…and what moves the world around these man-made realms of greed is in its short, power. It consumes their minds and makes them do the unthinkable, the more they get the more they seek in all the endless ways that they can fathom. And do not get me wrong dear reader, i am in no way trying to draw excuses for their devious behaviors, in fact, i despise them to my core, and wish upon them the ugliest forms of torture for what the have done, for what they have not to stop this madness. “20 minute lunch break and we will resume afterwards” the sickening irony as you arabs gather around fancy feasts as more babies will get killed before finding a bite to eat, the same babies you gathered in your pretend fiasco to save.</p><p>Did we put the wrong men in charge? We have been for centuries, but how could we have not seen the rotting evil behind those voided dark eyes, the same eyes that see the piles of blood and bone and command for more, “MORE MORE! We want to build skyscrapers and theme parks with their bones”, were we also consumed in greed by their empty promises?. Maybe but certainly we are victims too, victims to the middle class and lower life-long curse, and yet we are not the ones being bombed to death day and night, forced to watch our families die…starve and freeze in shallow tents. And no solution, no truce, will save them from the unimaginable pain and heart ache that will settle down on them once this round of war is over, once the emptiness of all they have lost from souls and fortune kicks in…can you imagine? Your house several footsteps echoing less, or perhaps, not echoing at all…i read a phrase 40 days of war earlier that deeply resonated in me: “who will open the door for the kids knocking coming home from school in Gaza? They haven’t left anyone to knock the door or open the door” and mind you, they haven’t even spared the door. </p><p>If you have experienced death around you, you may know that there is a bitter comfort in saying your last goodbye to a loved one, getting the chance to conclude a life-time of their existence and resonate the feeling that they have moved on, so you can mourn in peace. My heart aches as i know that thousands of my brothers and sisters in Gaza did not get the chance, the bare minimum to ease their pain turned to an open wound that will never shut. Instead, they were faced with body bags filled with limps and uncertainty whether the child in that bag is their own, “what if he is still out there somewhere under the rubble, what if he is still alive?”. At some point, it became a privilege to end up in a body bag, because the alternative is to lay under the weight of what used to be your home fading away un-found as your corpse decays to bones. </p><p>Is death more merciful in these times? I presume many wish for it and i wonder if i would too, mind you reader i keep asking these questions as i myself can not imagine being in their place, they are people just as normal as you and i and yet, they have experienced the worst of what humanity has to offer. I couldn’t imagine being faced with a doctor about to cut off my limps or ease my burning flesh without anesthesia,…they ran out, as they are running out of all life essentials, the whole world in its might and power can not order to allow help to go in (or it may not align with their agenda, vile vile world) let alone stop the war entirely.</p><p>It has been proven that Israel has a major influence in the world, rotting evil veining in every direction and on every level, it would be ridiculous to not assume this mastermind plan has been going on from the beginning, 75 years of torture and humiliation of my people over what is rightfully theirs… and if you have by now, as i hope you have, stepped away from the pit of lies they have so masterfully catered for you, then the screams of thousands of oppressed indigenous people will come out shouting back at you.</p><p>It is in the nature we were created for, that we shall live on this earth as successors generation after generation to benefit ourselves and others. It is in the human nature to look after each other and all of God’s creation. In other words, let us all count our blessings with every passing breath that we continue to live a “normal” life, let us use those precious breaths to speak up louder and further on the injustice happening right under our noses. I damn you a life time of miserable mediocrity if you think this does not concern you, how do you know you are not next? Did you find comfort in your overrated, overpriced blood thirsty coffees? does it feel like a fresh good morning when thousands of children didn’t wake up that day? </p><p>Those heroes i see everyday come in many shapes and forms, some wear sandals running from one bombing to another, some barefoot carrying their feline friends to safety, and some of which wear blue vests…the same blue vests behind every lens you see this monstrosity through. It is a most noble act to carry the truth as honest as you can, and even more furtherly noble when you choose to risk your life for it, but again, have they even a choice? “Not all heroes wear capes, some wear blue vests” and in these heroes we collectively put in a thousand blessings of gratitude for that their images, single handed alternated the outlook of the war on Gaza specifically, and Palestinians generally. Oh how proud and blessed i am to be Palestinian living on this holy land, in my veins runs the same courageous blood scattered vividly on the eastern coast of the Mediterranean…just a little to the south.</p><p>“No one is spared, not even the animals” as the video shows a heavily injured cat laying silently on the cold aftermath of destruction, not even the voiceless, most innocent creatures were spared, a horse carrying the freshly injured victims to the hospital was bombed relentlessly immobile to the ground…who will aid the injured? Who will feed the rest? When all there is left are dire piles of stones. They used to have lovely homes to roam, now they hopelessly roam the empty streets in doomed attempts to find scraps. </p><p>01/01/2024, peace be upon your precious souls that gracefully joined the one and only savior above all, may you find a most deserved eternity of peace and comfort in the hands of the most powerful among your loved ones once more, where laughter never stops echoing and food never runs out, how I imagine you all on the sands of a glistening sea, finally enjoying it without fear, what is rightfully yours will always find its way back to you, God will make sure of that, and in God we place our trust. </p><p>Silly isn’t it? We enter a new year in this blip of time and the rockets continue to go up, but not the kind that shoot out pretty lights.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;iframe height=&quot;250&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PwHr_vmW-oo&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="diary" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/diary/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to modify referer header in Chrome</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/how-to-modify-referer-header/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/how-to-modify-referer-header/</id>
    <published>2023-09-17T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-17T20:10:10.373Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you access a website or make a request to a web server using your browser, it sends various HTTP headers as part of the request. One of these headers is the “Referer” header, which tells the server the URL of the page that referred you to the current page.</p><p>While this header serves a legitimate purpose, there are times when you might want to modify or suppress it for privacy or testing reasons. In this article, I will talk about my experience in how to change the Referer header in a request sent in the Chrome browser.</p><span id="more"></span><p><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: Modifying the Referer header can have privacy and security implications, and it may violate the terms of service of some websites. Ensure you are aware of the legal and ethical considerations when using this technique, and use it responsibly.</p><p>My task was to build a private application for a specific user, and part of this application’s functionality involves loading data from another websites into their own when clicking a buttom in their admin page.</p><p>Since the web application I’m building is a private one, the simplest way I can do to read data from other websites is to disable CORS web security feature in chrome browser and send fetch requests to other domains. By doing this, I won’t get any CORS complaints when I read data from other websites.</p><p>One of the website from which I need to fetch data has a strict security measure in place: they only process requests sent from their own domain; if a request was send from another domain, they will return an error message indicating that the referer header mismatches with their domain name.</p><p>The biggest challenge in my task was to find a simple way to override the referer header sent in the request. I should mention here that there are other solutions that I can do to read the data from their website like building an external service outside the browser environment that fetches the data for me or like building a chrome extension the overrides the referer header, however I was looking for the simplest way to access the other website data without the need to buind an external service or app to do that.</p><p>Modern web browsers, including Chrome, do not allow you to directly modify the Referer header for security and privacy reasons. The Referer header is automatically generated by the browser based on the URL of the page that initiated the request, and it cannot be overridden via JavaScript when making requests using the Fetch API or even XMLHttpRequest.</p><p>The Referer header is an important security feature that helps websites protect against Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) attacks and prevents unauthorized access to certain resources. Allowing web pages to modify the Referer header could introduce significant security vulnerabilities.</p><p>But there’s one way you can use to modify the auto generated <code>referer</code> header in chrome, which is by modifying the browser history. The trick is very simple. When sending a request to another domain, the browser sets the value of the <code>Referer</code> header to the current page url set in the browser’s address bar. So what we need to do is changing the url in the address bar without reloading the page content, and we can do that using the JS History API.</p><p>I used <code>window.history.replaceState</code> to change the Referer header indirectly by changing the URL in the browser’s address bar. Here’s how I did it:</p><figure class="highlight js"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br><span class="line">16</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment">// This sample code shows how to modify referer header to `example.com` while I&#x27;m in `mywebsite.com`</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="keyword">const</span> readData = <span class="keyword">async</span>() =&gt; &#123;</span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">const</span> pageToReadDataFrom = <span class="string">&#x27;https://example.com/page-to-read-data-from&#x27;</span>;</span><br><span class="line">    </span><br><span class="line">    <span class="comment">// Store the current location to come back to it later</span></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">const</span> originalLocation = <span class="built_in">window</span>.location.href;</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="comment">// Replace address bar url domain name</span></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="built_in">window</span>.history.replaceState(<span class="literal">null</span>, <span class="string">&#x27;&#x27;</span>, <span class="string">&#x27;https://example.com/&#x27;</span>);</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="comment">// Read data from example.com website, the referer header will be sit to `example.com`</span></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="keyword">let</span> result = <span class="keyword">await</span> fetch(pageToReadDataFrom).then(<span class="function"><span class="params">res</span> =&gt;</span> res.json()).then(<span class="function"><span class="params">res</span> =&gt;</span> &#123;<span class="comment">/*Do whatever I want with the result here*/</span>&#125;);</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="comment">// Restore original url in the address bar.</span></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="built_in">window</span>.history.replaceState(<span class="literal">null</span>, <span class="string">&#x27;&#x27;</span>, originalLocation);</span><br><span class="line">&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Please note that this can be only done while cors protection is disabled in your chrome browser(by running chrome with the <code>--disable-web-security</code> flag). If you did not do that, you will get a CORS error similar to this one:</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">Uncaught DOMException: Failed to execute &#39;replaceState&#39; on &#39;History&#39;: A history state object with URL &#39;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;example.com&#x2F;&#39; cannot be created in a document with origin &#39;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mywebsite.com&#39; and URL &#39;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;mywebsite.com&#x2F;wp-admin&#x2F;&#39;.</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>In the world of web development, innovative solutions often arise from the need to overcome unique challenges. Modifying the Referer header in Chrome, as explored in this article, was a very exciting challenge to solve. Leveraging the JavaScript History API with <code>window.history.replaceState</code> offers a workaround to adjust the Referer header indirectly, proving invaluable in certain cross-domain data loading scenarios.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When you access a website or make a request to a web server using your browser, it sends various HTTP headers as part of the request. One of these headers is the “Referer” header, which tells the server the URL of the page that referred you to the current page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this header serves a legitimate purpose, there are times when you might want to modify or suppress it for privacy or testing reasons. In this article, I will talk about my experience in how to change the Referer header in a request sent in the Chrome browser.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="technical" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/technical/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Eight Months in Review; A Progress Update</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/birthday-progress/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/birthday-progress/</id>
    <published>2023-09-12T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-11T19:30:18.643Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As we’ve approached the conclusion of the first eight months of 2023, this is an overview of the progress and accomplishments achieved during the last 8 months.</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Relocation"><a href="#Relocation" class="headerlink" title="Relocation"></a>Relocation</h2><p>The biggest achievement I had in the last year was moving to Germany and starting in a new job in Hamburg. Moving to a new country is very exciting, but it also has many challenges. The biggest challenge that faced me when I moved to Hamburg was finding a good flat to rent.</p><p>Hamburg, as a major economic hub in Germany, has a large and diverse population over the years. Consequently, securing a flat in this vibrant state was a notably arduous endeavor, with high demand far surpassing the available housing options.</p><p>Despite the difficulties of finding an apartment in the crowded city, I was luckily able to change my apartment 2 times in the last 8 months. And even though moving to a new apartment could be very annoying when you are worried about finding a flat in time and moving your things from the old flat to the new one, but from the accessibility to everything in the city center to the beautiful nature in the city suburbs, I surly enjoy it when I settle in the new apartment and start exploring new places and nature in the new area.</p><p>I’ve also developed new hobbies based on the location that I lived in; I used to visit new famous places in the city that I’ve never been to when I lived in the city center, and I’ve starting hiking around the forest and riding my bike more aften when I lived in the state side.</p><p>The good news is that I can enjoy both biking and exploring new places in the city from my current apartment; I love my current apartment and I’m not planning to relocate to another one in the near future.</p><h2 id="Personal-projects"><a href="#Personal-projects" class="headerlink" title="Personal projects"></a>Personal projects</h2><p>Learning new technologies and frameworks is something essential to expand my knowledge in my field. The way I learn new things is by working on developing open source and side projects. Working on external and personal projects also helps to keep me up to date with the latest technologies used in my field.</p><p>Unfortunately, due to been busy with the relocation and the new job that I had, I didn’t get the chance to work on many side projects this year. This should be a goal for the future.</p><p>I managed however to work on one personal project in the last 8 months; it’s a service I build and deployed online, and it’s currently accessed more than 6,000 times monthly based on Google Search console statistics.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/birthday-progress/personal-website-analytics.png"></p><p>The service is not only gaining more users every month, but also gaining more money too 💰. It’s a mini service and I don’t think it will earn a lot of money in the future, but it’s very nice the idea that you’ve came up with an idea and to see other people using it and to see it giving you some revenue 😎.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/birthday-progress/personal-website-adsense.png"></p><p>I’m getting more busy with work and other life aspects recently, but nevertheless I should focus more on this project and spend more time on it.</p><h2 id="Dota-2"><a href="#Dota-2" class="headerlink" title="Dota 2"></a>Dota 2</h2><p>I’m playing more Dota 2 and sleeping less nowadays ✌️. I’ve played more ranked games this year and I’m loosing more MMR each and every day :3</p><p>One of the things I focused on in the last 8 months is playing with heroes that I haven’t picked before. I randomly pick heroes in many of my matches to try out new heroes, and because of that I now play more with heroes I was always hesitant to play with like Enigma, Spectre &amp; Templar Assasin.</p><p>Randomly picking heroes is a good idea to learn how play with other heroes, but it’s also one of the reasons why I lose MMR in my ranked games 😂.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/birthday-progress/dota2.png"></p><p>Even though my carrying skills has increased recently, I would always prefer to pick a support hero in the game. There are many skills that I still didn’t master that carry players need to have, like how tf can someone buy an item in less than 10 mins or 15 mins from the begining of the game! Or how can they keep farming and fighting at the same time!! I usually fail to buy enough items for my hero even though I try to farm as much as I can :(.</p><p>Dota 2 is becoming more and more crazy with each update they release, and Valve Dota2 team knows perfectly how to add new insane abilities to heroes that will ruin others game.</p><p>I also enjoy watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DotaWatafak">Dota Watafak</a> videos; a channel that collect clips from thousands of dota players from all over the world. </p><p>I feel sometimes that playing Dota 2 impacts my concentration in the morning, specially when I keep playing it for a very late time in the evening. Dota 2 is my biggest waste of time, and I don’t think I will ever consider stop playing it anytime in the future 🎮. I’ve found out recently that one of the engineers in my team also plays Dota 2, so I shall go in more parties with him in the future 💪</p><h2 id="See-the-world-🌎"><a href="#See-the-world-🌎" class="headerlink" title="See the world 🌎"></a>See the world 🌎</h2><p>I am absolutely pumped about the idea of exploring all the awesome places in Europe! 😃 Sadly, I’ve used up all my vacation days for now, but I’m counting down the days until next year when I can finally start my European adventure. 🗓️ The thought of diving into Europe’s rich history, diverse cultures, and stunning landscapes has me buzzing with excitement. 🌍 From strolling through the lively streets of Paris 🥖🇫🇷 to getting lost in the beauty of Norway 🇳🇴, I just can’t wait to kickstart this amazing journey. So, even though I have to be patient for a bit longer, I know it’s going to be totally worth it, and I’ll be making some incredible memories along the way! 🌟🌏</p><h2 id="Sports"><a href="#Sports" class="headerlink" title="Sports"></a>Sports</h2><p>Living alone in a new country can be a unique challenge, and for me, staying active has become an absolute necessity for a good mental and physical health.</p><p>The lack of movement feels suffocating; it’s as though my very existence depends on it. Back when I arrived in Hamburg, I didn’t immediately find a gym like I used to have in Palestine, and I was also very busy with the relocation and all other chalenges I faced here.</p><p>However, I’ve discovered later the beauty of staying active in different ways. Now, I find myself frequently pedaling 🚴 along the scenic Alster Lake or on the facinating old Harburg bridge on my bike, savoring the tranquility it offers. I also try to bike to work if I wake up early in the morning and we have a nice weather outside.</p><p>I like to listen to music when I go cycling 🎵. My playlist changes every couple of months. I remember I used to listem to songs like Titanium, Immprtals, The promissed Neverland OP, AOT OST, I really like you cover, Hall of fame, &amp; my League of Legends playlist 🔥.</p><iframe height="250" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KbNL9ZyB49c" style="width:100%;"></iframe><p>Additionally, I’ve embraced boxing lessons 🥊, which not only keep me physically fit but also provide a great mental release. Sometimes, I even push myself to the limits by doing some boxing after work, followed by a late-night bike ride, and I must say, there’s an exhilarating freedom in those moments that I absolutely cherish!</p><h2 id="Food"><a href="#Food" class="headerlink" title="Food"></a>Food</h2><p>I used to eat a lot of food and follow some good health habits regarding the food I eat. I maintained the same food habits for the first 5 months after I first came to hamburg.</p><p>But nowadays I barely eat anything. I even look at myself and wonder how am I still alive with the low food rations I eat 😶. My assumption for why is that happening to me is probably because my body is set on the battery saver mode 🔋.</p><p>I still enjoy eating food. I cook sometimes, and I go from time to time to restaurants in Steindamm &amp; Altona and enjoy a happy eastern meal there.</p><h2 id="Luca"><a href="#Luca" class="headerlink" title="Luca"></a>Luca</h2><p>Luca is a chrome extension built on top of react to watching movies with friends. You can <a href="/luca">find out more about Luca here</a>.</p><p>I stopped working on Luca after the relocation, and everytime I was going to back it it, I couldn’t continue working on it cause I need a designer to help me with UI.</p><p>Luca is the project that will make me become a millionaire. I should stop waisting my time and continue working on it 🤦. One of my next goals for the next year should be continue working on Luca. There are some features that should be added to the UI, the server needs to be more stable, and I need to start working on the mobile app.</p><p><a href="javascript:lucaTreasureHunt()">Click me if you’re interested in the Luca project</a>.</p><h2 id="freiheit-com"><a href="#freiheit-com" class="headerlink" title="freiheit.com"></a>freiheit.com</h2><p>Joining freiheit.com is my biggest achievement for the last year. You can <a href="/freiheit-com">read more about my experience @ freiheit.com here</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we’ve approached the conclusion of the first eight months of 2023, this is an overview of the progress and accomplishments achieved during the last 8 months.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="diary" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/diary/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Working @ freiheit.com</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/freiheit-com/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/freiheit-com/</id>
    <published>2023-08-31T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-07T15:08:53.414Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ten months ago, I embarked on a new chapter of my life, moving to the vibrant city of Hamburg. This marked not only a change in my location but also a significant step in my career as a software engineer. I was fortunate to join Freiheit, an IT company headquartered in Hamburg, and today, I want to share my journey and experiences with this remarkable organization and the beautiful city I now call home.</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Discovering-freiheit-com"><a href="#Discovering-freiheit-com" class="headerlink" title="Discovering freiheit.com"></a>Discovering freiheit.com</h2><p>Upon my arrival in Hamburg, I was eager to dive into my new role as a software engineer at freiheit.com. From the very beginning, I felt a sense of belonging and camaraderie among the team members. The company’s culture exuded inclusivity, collaboration, and a genuine passion for technology. The people I met were not only highly skilled but also incredibly humble and experienced, making it a nurturing environment for personal and professional growth.</p><h2 id="My-Role-as-a-Software-Engineer"><a href="#My-Role-as-a-Software-Engineer" class="headerlink" title="My Role as a Software Engineer"></a>My Role as a Software Engineer</h2><p>As a software engineer at freiheit.com, I had the privilege of working on a very exciting project from it’s very early stages that pushed the boundaries of my technical and soft expertise. One of the most significant learning experiences was working with microservices and learning new things about their concept.</p><p>Additionally, I had the opportunity to work with tools like K9s and Protocol Buffers (ProtoBuf). These tools not only enhanced my skill set but also enabled me to contribute more effectively to the projects I was involved in. The constant exposure to new technologies and methodologies kept my passion for software engineering burning brightly.</p><h2 id="Mentoring-and-Growth"><a href="#Mentoring-and-Growth" class="headerlink" title="Mentoring and Growth"></a>Mentoring and Growth</h2><p>One of the aspects that sets freiheit.com apart is its commitment to nurturing talent. I was entrusted with the responsibility of supervising a new member who joined our team. This experience allowed me to further develop my leadership skills and share the knowledge I had acquired during my tenure. It was a gratifying experience to see my mentee grow and thrive within our organization.</p><h2 id="Exploring-Hamburg"><a href="#Exploring-Hamburg" class="headerlink" title="Exploring Hamburg"></a>Exploring Hamburg</h2><p>Beyond the confines of the office, I found immense joy in exploring the city of Hamburg. The city’s rich history, stunning architecture, and diverse neighborhoods never ceased to amaze me. I often took leisurely walks or bike rides, discovering new places every day. From the iconic Elbphilharmonie to the picturesque Alster Lake, Hamburg offered a multitude of experiences that enriched my life outside of work.</p><h1 id="Conclusion"><a href="#Conclusion" class="headerlink" title="Conclusion"></a>Conclusion</h1><p>My journey with freiheit.com and Hamburg has been nothing short of remarkable. I have grown as a software engineer, deepened my understanding of innovative technologies, and formed lasting connections with my colleagues. Hamburg, with its charm and beauty, has become my beloved home.</p><p>As I continue my career with freiheit.com, I look forward to the challenges and opportunities that lie ahead. The company’s commitment to excellence and personal growth aligns perfectly with my aspirations, and I am excited to see where this journey leads me next.</p><p>My time at freiheit.com in Hamburg has been a journey of professional fulfillment and personal exploration. I am grateful for the experiences, the knowledge gained, and the friendships formed. Hamburg’s “Freiheit” (freedom) has truly become a guiding principle in both my career and my life.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ten months ago, I embarked on a new chapter of my life, moving to the vibrant city of Hamburg. This marked not only a change in my location but also a significant step in my career as a software engineer. I was fortunate to join Freiheit, an IT company headquartered in Hamburg, and today, I want to share my journey and experiences with this remarkable organization and the beautiful city I now call home.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="diary" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/diary/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Luca</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/luca/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/luca/</id>
    <published>2022-05-22T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-27T04:49:26.782Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m happy to share the news with everyone that we’re currently working on the development of Luca; a chrome extension built on top of react to watching movies with friends 🎥. Using Luca, you can create parties 🎉, invite friends👬, sync movie player▶️, chat with friends💬, send reactions😂, and do many more things.</p><span id="more"></span><p>Our goal with Luca is to allow friends to watch any online video with friends without the need to upload the video to any third party website or application 💃.</p><p>We’re also planning to expand Luca to other platforms. Our goal is for everyone to run Luca on Chrome / Edge / Safari / Firefox / Android / IOS.</p><p>Luca is completely free and open source 👾. We welcome all kind of contributions to the chrome extension code and design. Drop Luca’s repo a visit on GitHub <a href="https://github.com/abozanona/luca">https://github.com/abozanona/luca</a>.</p><p>You can try the latest version of Luca from <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/obnoakbedffbolampagecgineggakiii">Chrome Web Store</a>. If you have an issue, bug or suggestions, don’t hesitate to open an issue with it on Github using <a href="https://github.com/abozanona/luca/issues">this link</a> or sending us your feedback on our discord server.</p><p>We also have a discord channel! It’s still new, and we want to build a big community there, so we welcome all of you to <a href="https://discord.com/invite/T3uvQupA">join us there</a>.</p><p>Luca was made with love thanks to <a href="https://github.com/abozanona">@abozanona</a>, <a href="https://github.com/Mahmoud-Skafi">@Mahmoud-Skafi</a> &amp; <a href="https://github.com/yousefra">@yousefra</a>.</p><p>Big thanks for <a href="https://cotede.co/">Co.Te.De Technologies</a> for their support on the Luca extension.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to share the news with everyone that we’re currently working on the development of Luca; a chrome extension built on top of react to watching movies with friends 🎥. Using Luca, you can create parties 🎉, invite friends👬, sync movie player▶️, chat with friends💬, send reactions😂, and do many more things.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="project" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/project/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hsoub Mobile Application</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/hsoub/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/hsoub/</id>
    <published>2021-10-03T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-01T22:25:13.934Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m happy to announce that I’m currently working on the development of a mobile application for <a href="https://io.hsoub.com/">Hsoub</a> website. Using the mobile application, you can browse Hsoub website and use all of the features of the original website.</p><span id="more"></span><p>The source code for the android application will be available on my <a href="https://github.com/abozanona/hsoub">GitHub repository</a>, and I welcome all kind of contributions to the application code and design.</p><p>You can try the alpha version of the application from <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rond.hsoub">Google Play store</a>. If you have an issue, bug or suggestions, don’t hesitate to open an issue with it on Github using this link <a href="https://github.com/abozanona/hsoub/issues">https://github.com/abozanona/hsoub/issues</a> . The mobile application will be available for ios on it’s release version</p><p>Hsoub application with be the first in a series of creating mobile applications for all of <a href="https://www.hsoub.com/">hsoub</a> websites.</p><p>Big thanks to <a href="https://io.hsoub.com/u/sasini">Sasini</a> for his design for the Hsoub application. You can see the original designs for Sasani on <a href="https://fnkeely.com/15534/%d8%aa%d8%b5%d9%85%d9%8a%d9%85-%d8%b4%d8%b9%d8%a7%d8%b1-%d9%88%d9%88%d8%a7%d8%ac%d9%87%d8%a9-%d8%aa%d8%b7%d8%a8%d9%8a%d9%82-%d8%ad%d8%b3%d9%88%d8%a8-io/">fnkeely</a>.</p><hr><h2 id="Update-24-01-2022"><a href="#Update-24-01-2022" class="headerlink" title="Update 24/01/2022"></a>Update 24/01/2022</h2><p>I received a message from Hsoub asking to remove the test app I published on Google play, so I will stop working on the app.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/hsoub/hsoub.png"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to announce that I’m currently working on the development of a mobile application for &lt;a href=&quot;https://io.hsoub.com/&quot;&gt;Hsoub&lt;/a&gt; website. Using the mobile application, you can browse Hsoub website and use all of the features of the original website.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="project" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/project/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>My cat</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/my-cat/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/my-cat/</id>
    <published>2021-09-20T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-06T20:20:51.061Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first time I met my cat was a few years ago. She was a kitten back then. I guess she was three or four months old. I found her in the house yard without a sign for her mother or siblings, so I decided to try to gain her trust and become her human friend. It was not the first time I tried to get closer to cats and be her friend. So I had a little experience in how can I get her trust. I managed to gain her trust by giving her food and gradually getting closer to her.</p><span id="more"></span><p>My mother doesn’t like cats at all; she doesn’t allow me to have pets inside our home, so in the first few weeks with my new cat, she used to pass by our house every day looking for me and hoping that I will bring her something to eat or she will sit in my lap and I will cuddle and pet her. After a while, I started sneaking her into our house frequently, keeping her inside the guest’s room, and bringing her some food to eat. And she used to sneak into our home by herself also. She would always go inside our house if she found the front door opened. She will go after that either to the kitchen to look for some food or to the guest’s room where I used to hide her from my mother.</p><p>She wasn’t only my cat. I saw her many times sitting in front of my uncle’s house waiting for my cousin to get her some food. But I think I was her favorite human friend. Between all of the humans she knew, I think she has spent most of her time with me. She sits a lot in my lap, she keeps rubbing her body with me, saying that she claims me, and she bites me from time to time. And whenever one of my two nephews sees her, he calls me and asks me to help him feeding her or playing with her. I’ve also taught her a small trick to be able to call her and make her come to me if she’s somewhere close to me. Whenever I snap my fingers she immediately comes to me. I used to snap my finger everytime I gave her something to eat, so whenever I snap my fingers she runs towards me asking for food.</p><iframe height="250" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K83ZiPpUr9c" style="width:100%;"></iframe><p>As far as I know, my cat has given birth three times. The first time she gave birth was more than three or four years ago. She sneaked into the guest’s room and gave birth to her children in an empty flower’s basket. My mother got very angry at me that day when she saw the blood in the guest’s room, and I was so thrilled because I finally had grandchildren :3. I had to move my cat out of the guest’s room and find them another place to stay in. I remember that day I tried to get her away from her kittens so I could move them, but she refused to leave her babies. I tried to offer her some food to eat and distract her but she didn’t eat anything. And when I held the basket to move her babies outside the house, she became very angry and started hissing at me. I moved my cat and her babies to somewhere else I prepared for them, and visited them frequently to give them some food and check my grandchildren. Few weeks later, she changed the location of her kittens to another place and I haven’t seen them after that. But I had the feeling that they couldn’t make it, and they have died few months after she has changed their location 😞.</p><p>The second time my cat had given birth was also in the guest’s room. It was two years ago. She gave birth in the same basket she gave birth in the first time. My mom was mad at me again :/ and I had to move them somewhere else. I built a small house with a barrel surrounding a tree. I made sure that the house is clean, has moderate temperature, and that it’s very difficult for her to grab her children from their necks, climb the tree and change their location again. And I kept visiting my cat and bring some food with me for her and her kitten.</p><p>After few weeks, I found my cat’s kitten inside the guest’s room; She has sneaked into the guest’s room from the opened window and moved all of her four kittens there. I tried to return them back to their previous house, but she moved them again to the yard in front of the guest’s room window. I tried to keep my cat and her kitten in the guest’s room for a couple of days, but I was exposed after that and I had to move them out again, and whenever I get them out of the house, my cat tries to sneak her kittens to the guest’s room again.</p><iframe height="250" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nK1C1ns2JTM" style="width:100%;"></iframe>  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ALDBzB_Tjmg" target="_blank">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ALDBzB_Tjmg</a><br/><br/>  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LODf85FN2Pk" target="_blank">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LODf85FN2Pk</a><br/><br/><p>I’ve learned a lot about cats with my cat and her four kittens. I remember one day she was sitting on the couch in the guest’s room watching me playing with her children, and she suddenly walked towards me and started licking me. I found out at that time how much does she love me. I’ve also learned some tricks of how I can limp and relax her kittens while I’m holding them and prevent them from struggling me, however that trick didn’t always work, and they scratch my hand sometimes.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/my-cat/my-cat.png"></p><p>Sadly, all of the four kittens have died 😞. It was a very stupid idea of me to allow my cat to keep her kittens around my house. All of the four kittens died because of that decision. Two of the kittens have died while my nephews were playing with them. When I arrived home that night, I was told that two of the kittens had died, and that my nephew feels sad and regrets that. He promised me that from now on he will never allow anyone from his friends to play with the other two kittens and that he will be nice with them. The other two kittens have died a couple of months later 😞. I feel very sorry for my cat 😞 She’s the saddest cat I have ever seen.</p><p>After her four kittens had died, I knew that the best thing for my cat is for her to live away from humans. I stopped giving her food as much as I used to do, stopped sneaking her inside the house, stopped cuddling her ,and stopped allowing her to sleep in my lap anymore. I remember that after few months her looks has changed to me. Whenever I meet her in the street, she keeps looking at me waiting for me to do something like ordering her to follow me by snapping my fingers or going towards her and holding her or massaging her head.</p><p>The third time she gave birth was around a month ago. I knew that after I saw her on the street and saw her belly dangling, which means she has given birth not a long time ago. I felt happy for her because she has given birth to her kittens away from humans.</p><p>I saw my cat few days after that with three little kittens around her, they had a different color from their previous brothers. In her first and second birth, her kittens had a yellow/golden hair color just like their mother’s, but in her last birth, all of her kitten’s hair color was gray.</p><p>And a week ago, after I arrived home, I noticed that she has moved her kittens to our house’s yard.</p><iframe height="250" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jgpif1I0NiY" style="width:100%;"></iframe><p>It was so sad to see two of the three kittens with her 😞. I offered them some food, tried to play with my cat’s children but they were scared of me and they didn’t get close to me without their mother coming closer to me at first. After they finished their meal, I moved them to somewhere else.</p><iframe height="250" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tnvSKN3zoKc" style="width:100%;"></iframe><p>I’ve noticed today that my cat has moved her kittens to another place, and I think this is the best thing she has made for her new kittens.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first time I met my cat was a few years ago. She was a kitten back then. I guess she was three or four months old. I found her in the house yard without a sign for her mother or siblings, so I decided to try to gain her trust and become her human friend. It was not the first time I tried to get closer to cats and be her friend. So I had a little experience in how can I get her trust. I managed to gain her trust by giving her food and gradually getting closer to her.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="diary" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/diary/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Github pull requests</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/github-pull-requests/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/github-pull-requests/</id>
    <published>2021-09-01T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-06T21:57:54.502Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I work on developing a new project, I always look for open source libraries and projects on Github to save me from reinventing the wheel. But in some cases, the code has issues or doesn’t fulfill my project requirements, and that’s when I modify the original code and create pull requests with my changes. <span id="more"></span> Here are some of the pull requests I’ve created on Github in the past years.</p><h2 id="Flutter-Cupertino-Date-Picker"><a href="#Flutter-Cupertino-Date-Picker" class="headerlink" title="Flutter Cupertino Date Picker. "></a>Flutter Cupertino Date Picker. <a href="https://github.com/imshashank/flutter-cupertino-date-picker/pull/2"><i class="fab fa-github"></i></a></h2><p>Flutter Cupertino Date Picker is a package that adds a nice Cupertino date picker to your Flutter application.</p><p>I used this library in one of my freelancing projects to display a nice datepicker to the users.</p><p>In my pull request, I fixed a typo in an Arabic word, and I fixed one line of code that was deprecated in the flutter version I was using in my project.</p><h2 id="Chrome-Response-Override"><a href="#Chrome-Response-Override" class="headerlink" title="Chrome Response Override. "></a>Chrome Response Override. <a href="https://github.com/Pasupathi-Rajamanickam/chrome-response-override/pull/9"><i class="fab fa-github"></i></a></h2><p>Chrome Response Override is a Chrome devtools extension to modify response on the fly. I recommend using this extension for ‘debugging’ a webpage response. This extension is a better option than downloading binaries for applications in order to be able to intercept and modify responses.</p><p>I saw a website that takes the user input and sends it to a service running on its server to serve the user request. The website encrypts the data on the browser and sends the encrypted data to the server. I guess that website was doing that to make it hard for developers to use their service by calling the service endpoint immediately.</p><p>It was a challenge for me to find out the code that is responsible for encrypting the request body before sending it to the server. With the help of <a href="https://github.com/Pasupathi-Rajamanickam/chrome-response-override">Chrome Response Override</a> extension, I was able to eliminate all files that has nothing to do with the encryption, and I was able to analyze a bundled script content and extract the part of code that encrypts the data 😄.</p><p>The extension was developed originally for replacing words in the response. I’ve made some modifications in the extension to add the support for replacing the whole code of a response. I’ve also added <a href="https://codemirror.net/">CodeMirror</a> code editor to make it easy to modify the code from Chrome devtools.</p><h2 id="Story-View"><a href="#Story-View" class="headerlink" title="Story View. "></a>Story View. <a href="https://github.com/blackmann/story_view"><i class="fab fa-github"></i></a></h2><p>Story View is a flutter widget to display stories just like Whatsapp and Instagram. I used this package in one of my projects where I needed to develop a story in users profiles. I’m very grateful for <a href="https://github.com/blackmann">Degreat</a> for this awesome package that he has developed.</p><p>The Story View package has an issue in supporting RTL. The story’s progress bars on the top doesn’t go from RTL. The gestures don’t change on RTL layout also. And gestures stop working when there’s a layout on top of it.</p><p>I also needed to add more functionalities to the story widget, including adding custom gestures like double click for like, and fix an issue where some of the content should be out of the mobile <a href="https://api.flutter.dev/flutter/widgets/SafeArea-class.html">SafeArea</a>.</p><p>I’ve made some modifications to the library to produce this new story view.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/github-pull-requests/story-view-1.png"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/github-pull-requests/story-view-2.png"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/github-pull-requests/story-view-3.png"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/github-pull-requests/story-view-4.png"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/github-pull-requests/story-view-5.png"></p><h2 id="Admob-Flutter"><a href="#Admob-Flutter" class="headerlink" title="Admob Flutter. "></a>Admob Flutter. <a href="https://github.com/kmcgill88/admob_flutter/pull/150"><i class="fab fa-github"></i></a></h2><p>I used this Admob Flutter package in one of my applications to show Admob ads on my application.</p><p>The package has an issue when compiling the IOS application, so I fixed the issue and created a pull request with my fix.</p><h2 id="Interactive-Webview"><a href="#Interactive-Webview" class="headerlink" title="Interactive Webview. "></a>Interactive Webview. <a href="https://github.com/abozanona/interactive_webview"><i class="fab fa-github"></i></a></h2><p>The Interactive Webview plugin allows Flutter to communicate with a native WebView. I had some issues running the package with my project, so I forked the repo, fix the issues of missing swift version and error in libraries import, and added the library from my <code>pubspec.yaml</code> file.</p><figure class="highlight yaml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="attr">dependencies:</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="attr">interactive_webview:</span></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="attr">git:</span></span><br><span class="line">      <span class="attr">url:</span> <span class="string">git://github.com/abozanona/interactive_webview.git</span></span><br><span class="line">      <span class="attr">ref:</span> <span class="string">master</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="Nativescript-ZXing"><a href="#Nativescript-ZXing" class="headerlink" title="Nativescript ZXing. "></a>Nativescript ZXing. <a href="https://github.com/abozanona/nativescript-zxing"><i class="fab fa-github"></i></a></h2><p>I needed to use both <a href="https://market.nativescript.org/plugins/nativescript-zxing/">nativescript-zxing</a> and <a href="https://market.nativescript.org/plugins/nativescript-barcodescanner/">nativescript-barcodescanner</a> in one of my NativeScript projects, and that caused a conflict between the two libraries. That’s why I had to modify the NativeScript ZXing repo code and resolve the code issue that causes the conflict between the two libraries.</p><p>In my package.json file, I imported nativescript-zxing from my Github repo instead of importing it from npm.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I work on developing a new project, I always look for open source libraries and projects on Github to save me from reinventing the wheel. But in some cases, the code has issues or doesn’t fulfill my project requirements, and that’s when I modify the original code and create pull requests with my changes.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="project" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/project/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Unstagram</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/unstagram/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/unstagram/</id>
    <published>2021-05-28T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T02:51:17.887Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of my friends on Instagram told me that he hates it so much when I read DM on Instagram and respond in a late time. That’s why I decided to build Unstagram! <span id="more"></span></p><p>Using Unstagram, you can read other’s messages on Instagram and they won’t know that. It works by blocking the seen request from been sent to Instagram server.</p><p>You can give it a try by downloading the chrome extension on your browser from <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/unstagram-instagram-messe/mfoefahdnhpopjcdmkpkncedcamplcei">here</a>.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my friends on Instagram told me that he hates it so much when I read DM on Instagram and respond in a late time. That’s why I decided to build Unstagram!</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="hack" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/hack/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Text To Speech</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/text-to-speech/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/text-to-speech/</id>
    <published>2021-04-18T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T00:15:06.346Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My brother studies English translations. He had an online quiz where he should memorize around 200 English words and their meaning in Arabic.</p><p>His teacher will tell him three words in Arabic and he should tell him the meaning in English. And then he will give him another three English words and my brother should give him the meaning in Arabic.</p><p>I wrote a python code with him to help him cheat in the quiz. :) </p><iframe height="250" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n-aDfbYzhl8" style="width:100%;"></iframe>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My brother studies English translations. He had an online quiz where he should memorize around 200 English words and their meaning in Ara</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="hack" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/hack/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Automatic typing</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/auto-typing/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/auto-typing/</id>
    <published>2020-12-01T22:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T02:45:52.361Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I forget a lot of things, and I’m a lazy person to save everything.</p><p>In my job, I’m required to enter a serial code everything I need to access a specific feature in the system. So instead of memorizing the serial code and write it down everything I want to access that feature in the system, I have decided to write a small code that will do the job for me. <span id="more"></span></p><p>I wrote a <code>bat</code> script that will simulate keys pressing on the keyboard and enter the serial number. The serial number is splitter into two parts, and it should be entered in two textboxes, and that’s what I told the script to do for me.</p><p>I created a new file <code>auto.bat</code>, and added the following script to it</p><figure class="highlight bat"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">@<span class="keyword">if</span> (@CodeSection == @Batch) @then</span><br><span class="line">@<span class="built_in">echo</span> off</span><br><span class="line"><span class="built_in">set</span> SendKeys=CScript //nologo //E:JScript &quot;%~F0&quot;</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment">rem start &quot;&quot; /B cmd</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="built_in">ping</span> -n <span class="number">1</span> -w <span class="number">1</span> <span class="number">127</span>.<span class="number">0</span>.<span class="number">0</span>.<span class="number">1</span> &gt; <span class="built_in">NUL</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="variable">%SendKeys%</span> &quot;<span class="variable">%%&#123;</span>TAB&#125;&quot;</span><br><span class="line"><span class="built_in">ping</span> -n <span class="number">1</span> -w <span class="number">1</span> <span class="number">127</span>.<span class="number">0</span>.<span class="number">0</span>.<span class="number">1</span> &gt; <span class="built_in">NUL</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="variable">%SendKeys%</span> &quot;SERIAL-CODE-PART-ONE&#123;TAB&#125;&quot;</span><br><span class="line"><span class="built_in">ping</span> -n <span class="number">1</span> -w <span class="number">1</span> <span class="number">127</span>.<span class="number">0</span>.<span class="number">0</span>.<span class="number">1</span> &gt; <span class="built_in">NUL</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="variable">%SendKeys%</span> &quot;SERIAL-CODE-PART-TWO&#123;ENTER&#125;&quot;</span><br><span class="line"><span class="keyword">goto</span> :EOF</span><br><span class="line">@end</span><br><span class="line">// JScript section</span><br><span class="line">var WshShell = WScript.CreateObject(&quot;WScript.Shell&quot;);</span><br><span class="line">WshShell.SendKeys(WScript.Arguments(<span class="number">0</span>));</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>After that, I create a new shortcut for that file, by going to desktop, clicking on the right mouse button, selecting Shortcut, and entering <code>auto.bat</code> full path.</p><p>Then I added a keyboard shortcut <code>Ctrl + Shift + Alt + P</code> to run the script by right-clicking on the shortcut file, going to Shortcut tap, and adding a shortcut key.</p><p>Now, whenever I want to access the system, I press the magical buttons <code>Ctrl + Shift + Alt + P</code> to ask my computer to enter the serial code for me.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I forget a lot of things, and I’m a lazy person to save everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my job, I’m required to enter a serial code everything I need to access a specific feature in the system. So instead of memorizing the serial code and write it down everything I want to access that feature in the system, I have decided to write a small code that will do the job for me.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="hack" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/hack/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Darcom</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/darcom/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/darcom/</id>
    <published>2020-03-09T22:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-01T22:25:13.933Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/darcom/darcom-home.png"></p><p><a href="https://darcom.ps/">Darcom</a> is a project I worked on as a freelancer. It’s a commercial advertising guide app. <span id="more"></span></p><p>With darcom you can:</p><ul><li>browser stores and orders products.</li><li>Collect points and get seasonal gifts.</li><li>Buy products from stores.</li><li>Share stories with your customers.</li><li>Send notifications to others.</li></ul><p>If you want to get new rewards every season, you can download Darcom from <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.darcom.darcom">Google Play</a> and <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/darcom/id1537964524">App Store</a> now.</p><p>If you are running a store and want an advertisement platform, you can download Darcom Business from <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.darcom.business">Google Play</a> and <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/darcom-business/id1540459395">App Store</a>.</p><p>Darcom was developed with Flutter and NodeJS.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/darcom/darcom-home.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://darcom.ps/&quot;&gt;Darcom&lt;/a&gt; is a project I worked on as a freelancer. It’s a commercial advertising guide app.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="project" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/project/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Videos streaming application</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/videos-streaming-application/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/videos-streaming-application/</id>
    <published>2019-08-17T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T02:52:36.191Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I worked on developing flutter Android and IOS applications for fetching and displaying videos from streaming websites through REST API <span id="more"></span></p><p>I used the Bloc State Management Library in the application development.</p><p>There’s no direct way to fetch Video streams from free video streaming websites, so I used multiple packages to parse pages HTML tags and execute JS scripts to be able to get video stream links.</p><p>The application does the following.</p><ul><li>View videos from streaming websites.</li><li>Search videos by name and category.</li><li>Create playlists for videos.</li><li>Create a new account on the application. Add videoes to persomal lists.</li><li>View video author profiles.</li><li>Search for similar videos.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I worked on developing flutter Android and IOS applications for fetching and displaying videos from streaming websites through REST API</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="project" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/project/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Nitro</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/nitro/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/nitro/</id>
    <published>2019-06-13T21:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-09-22T02:47:36.850Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Android-application"><a href="#Android-application" class="headerlink" title="Android application"></a>Android application</h1><p><a href="https://nitro.co.com/">Nitro</a> is an android application for advertising. The application is for Nitro company for media and advertisement. The application is downloaded on tablets that are setupped in the city taxis. The app loads advertisements from a server and displays them to people in the taxi. Ads are only shown to users when they are in a specific range with the advertiser store. <span id="more"></span></p><p>The application also creates a hotspot that all people in the taxi can connect to. The hotspot allows users to server limited websites and applications.</p><p>The application was developed using native android SDK.</p><p>One of the challenging features that was built in this application was preventing users from interacting with the application and tablet in all possible ways. Here are some of the ways I did that.</p><ul><li>Disabled interacting with hardware buttons.</li><li>Prevented the interaction with the screen.</li><li>Designed the application as a Launcher Application.</li><li>Removed lock screen.</li><li>Registered the application to the Accessibility Service to listen to and prevent all possible interactions with the device.</li><li>Ran a VPN on the tablet to limit web pages users can access.</li></ul><h1 id="Admin-panel"><a href="#Admin-panel" class="headerlink" title="Admin panel"></a>Admin panel</h1><p>There’s also an admin panel where admins can manage advertisers’ subscriptions and control displayed ads.</p><p>I user NodeJs to build the REST API and Angular to build the admin panel.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;Android-application&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Android-application&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Android application&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Android application&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nitro.co.com/&quot;&gt;Nitro&lt;/a&gt; is an android application for advertising. The application is for Nitro company for media and advertisement. The application is downloaded on tablets that are setupped in the city taxis. The app loads advertisements from a server and displays them to people in the taxi. Ads are only shown to users when they are in a specific range with the advertiser store.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="project" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/project/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tmasraf</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/tmasraf/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/tmasraf/</id>
    <published>2018-12-07T22:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-01T22:25:13.935Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/tmasraf/tmasraf-splash-screen.png"></p><p>Tmasraf is one of the projects I worked on as a freelancer. It’s a cashback mobile app where customers get points from shopping. <span id="more"></span></p><p>In Tmasraf, I developed two mobile applications(one for customers and one for merchants), and a control panel for admins.</p><p>Tmasraf was developed using NodeJS[Express] and NativeScript.</p><blockquote><p>The first version of the mobile application was developed using Xamarin.Forms, but I switched to NativeScript to improve application performance.</p></blockquote><h2 id="Tmasraf-admin-panel"><a href="#Tmasraf-admin-panel" class="headerlink" title="Tmasraf admin panel."></a>Tmasraf admin panel.</h2><p>The admin panel gives admins access to website statistics and allows them to manage merchants’ subscriptions.</p><h2 id="Tmasraf-customers-application"><a href="#Tmasraf-customers-application" class="headerlink" title="Tmasraf customers application."></a>Tmasraf customers application.</h2><p>Users can create a new account in Tmasraf customers application to access its features. Once users create an account they can start collecting points.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/tmasraf/tmasraf-user-profile.png"></p><p>Every new user gets a unique QR code that can be used in earning points.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/tmasraf/tmasraf-user-home.png"></p><p>Users can see a list of all subscribed stores in the application and explore their location and products.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/tmasraf/tmasraf-user-menu.png"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/tmasraf/tmasraf-user-stores.png"></p><p>Customers can earn a point from buying products from the subscribed stores by allowing the stores to scan their QR code from the merchant application. I implemented a secure method to transfer points between customers and merchants using QR code scanning.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/tmasraf/tmasraf-user-points.png"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/tmasraf/tmasraf-savings.png"></p><h2 id="Tmasraf-merchants-application"><a href="#Tmasraf-merchants-application" class="headerlink" title="Tmasraf merchants application."></a>Tmasraf merchants application.</h2><p>Merchants application is used by stores to add points to customers. When a customer buys a product from a merchant, the merchant scans the customer’s QR code and sends him cashback points that he can use in buying products in the future.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/tmasraf/tmasraf-store-scan-code.png"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/tmasraf/tmasraf-store-sell.png"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/tmasraf/tmasraf-splash-screen.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tmasraf is one of the projects I worked on as a freelancer. It’s a cashback mobile app where customers get points from shopping.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="project" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/project/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>College freelancing projects</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/optimum/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/optimum/</id>
    <published>2018-02-20T22:23:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-01T22:25:13.934Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was in my last year in college, I was introduced to <a href="https://www.paloptimum.ps/">Optimum</a>; a marketing agency located at Hebron. I contracted with them as a freelancer and worked on developing websites for companies and individuals they work within the media production. <span id="more"></span></p><h2 id="Al-Wafa-Plastic-Industries"><a href="#Al-Wafa-Plastic-Industries" class="headerlink" title="Al-Wafa Plastic Industries"></a>Al-Wafa Plastic Industries</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/wpi/wpi-home.jpg"></p><p>I developed <a href="https://wpi.ps/">WPI</a> website for Al-Wafa company to post their news and display their products catalogs to their customers.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/wpi/wpi-catalog.png"></p><p>Customers can also use a custom 3D wizard to design bottles and order them.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/wpi/wpi-wizard-1.jpg"></p><p>In the 3d wizard, customers can pick the product, its cap and color.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/wpi/wpi-wizard-2.jpg"></p><p>A custom Wordpress theme was developed for WPI website.</p><h2 id="Viviane"><a href="#Viviane" class="headerlink" title="Viviane"></a>Viviane</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/viviane/viviane-home.jpg"></p><p><a href="https://juneidi-ps.com/">Viviane</a> website was developed for Al-juneidi for water bottles. The website’s purpose is to post the latest company events and the company products.</p><p>A custom wordpress theme was also developed for Viviane website.</p><p>Viviane website has a <a href="https://juneidi-ps.com/game/">hidden link</a> to play the Viviane puzzle game.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/viviane/viviane-game-1.jpg"></p><p>The game was developed using Unity3D and was uploaded to Viviane website and Facebook Gaming Platform</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/viviane/viviane-game-2.jpg"></p><h2 id="Rahhal"><a href="#Rahhal" class="headerlink" title="Rahhal"></a>Rahhal</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/rahhal/rahhal-home.jpg"></p><p><strong>Rahhal</strong> was developed for a traveling man to post about his trips. The website was developed using MEAN stack technologies. I used express, gulp &amp; mongoose in website developemnt.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/rahhal/rahhal-visited-countries.png"></p><p>The admin can use the admin panel to create new galleries for his trips</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/rahhal/rahhal-gallery.jpg"></p><p>The admin can also write blogs about his trips to a continent or a country.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/rahhal/rahhal-continent.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/abozanona/abozanona.me/images/projects/rahhal/rahhal-blog.jpg"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was in my last year in college, I was introduced to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paloptimum.ps/&quot;&gt;Optimum&lt;/a&gt;; a marketing agency located at Hebron. I contracted with them as a freelancer and worked on developing websites for companies and individuals they work within the media production.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="project" scheme="https://abozanona.me/categories/project/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>About abozanona</title>
    <link href="https://abozanona.me/about/"/>
    <id>https://abozanona.me/about/</id>
    <published>1995-09-11T23:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-06T22:02:21.325Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi, I’m Abozanona, a quiet person, listens to classical music, likes old songs, and addicted to Dota2.</p><h2 id="Components"><a href="#Components" class="headerlink" title="Components"></a>Components</h2><table><thead><tr><th>element</th><th>feature</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>My Statement</td><td>Wind, love, code &amp; everything in between!</td></tr><tr><td>Statement I Like</td><td>Le vent se lève! … il faut tenter de vivre!</td></tr><tr><td>Birthday</td><td>12th September 1995</td></tr><tr><td>Characteristics</td><td>Busy, Slow to respond, Bad in memorization, Offline, Not using social websites</td></tr><tr><td>Career</td><td>Struts2 &amp; FullStack developer</td></tr><tr><td>Favorite Anime</td><td>Attack on Titan, duh (￣▽￣)</td></tr><tr><td>Favorite Game</td><td>Dota2</td></tr><tr><td>Favorite Food</td><td>I eat everything ♨</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="Programming-contests-amp-Participations"><a href="#Programming-contests-amp-Participations" class="headerlink" title="Programming contests &amp; Participations"></a>Programming contests &amp; Participations</h2><ul><li>2nd place in the  Schools Programming Olympic contest 2011 - Palestine.</li><li>Participant in ACM-PCPC contest for the years 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017.</li><li>1st place in ACM-PCPC contest 2017.</li><li>Coach of the 3rd place team in ACM-PCPC contest 2017.</li><li>Participated in ACM-Arab Collegiate Programming Contest 2017.</li><li>Participated in Google Code Jam 2017, 2018.</li><li>1st place in PPU programming contest 2017.</li><li>1st place in Hebron code jam 2017.</li><li>3rd place in Hebron code jam 2018.</li><li>Participated in Global Game jam for years 2016, 2017.</li><li>Participated in Game Jam Palestine Zanga for years 2014, 2016, 2017, 2019.</li><li>3rd place in Game Jam Palestine Zanga contest 2014.</li><li>4th place in Game Jam Palestine Zanga contest 2016.</li><li>Coordinator of Game Jam Palestine Zanga 2019.</li><li>Participated in Google HashCode 2018, 2020</li><li>Scored 3rd rank in Palestine, (1180 place overall) in Google HashCode 2020.</li></ul><h2 id="Things-I-worked-on"><a href="#Things-I-worked-on" class="headerlink" title="Things I worked on"></a>Things I worked on</h2><div class="work">    <div class="work-title">        Unstagram        <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/unstagram-instagram-messe/mfoefahdnhpopjcdmkpkncedcamplcei"><i class="fas fa-link"></i></a>        <a href="https://github.com/abozanona/Unstagram"><i class="fab fa-github"></i></a>    </div>    <div class="work-desc">Using Unstagram, you can read other’s messages on Instagram and they won’t know that.</div></div><div class="work">    <div class="work-title">        Darcom        <a href="https://darcom.ps/"><i class="fas fa-link"></i></a>    </div>    <div class="work-desc">Darcom is a commercial advertising guide app.</div></div><div class="work">    <div class="work-title">        Nitro        <a href="https://nitro.co.com/"><i class="fas fa-link"></i></a>    </div>    <div class="work-desc">Nitro is an android application for advertising in taxis.</div></div><div class="work">    <div class="work-title">        Tmasraf        <a href="https://nitro.co.com/"><i class="fas fa-link"></i></a>    </div>    <div class="work-desc">Tmasraf is a cashback mobile app where customers get points from shopping.</div></div><h2 id="Find-me"><a href="#Find-me" class="headerlink" title="Find me"></a>Find me</h2><p>🍭Contact &amp; Sponsorship：</p><ul><li><a href="mailto:abozanona@gmail.com?subject=That%20Astonishing%20Movie...&body=Hi%20Abozanona%2C%0D%0A%0D%0AI%20have%20found%20a%20movie%20%26%20I'm%20sure%20you'll%20love%20it!%0D%0AMaybe%20we%20should%20watch%20it%20together%3F%0D%0ALet%20me%20know%20when%20you're%20free!%0D%0A%0D%0AYagami%20Light.">Email me?</a></li><li><a href="mailto:abozanona@gmail.com?subject=That%20Astonishing%20Movie...&body=Hi%20Abozanona%2C%0D%0A%0D%0AI%20have%20found%20a%20movie%20%26%20I'm%20sure%20you'll%20love%20it!%0D%0AMaybe%20we%20should%20watch%20it%20together%3F%0D%0ALet%20me%20know%20when%20you're%20free!%0D%0A%0D%0AYagami%20Light.">Have an idea?</a></li><li><a href="/assets/abozanona-resume.pdf">Hire me?</a></li><li><a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/abozanon">Buy me a coffee?</a></li><li>Direct messaging? ¯\<em>(ツ)</em>/¯</li></ul><style>.post-body thead {    display: none;}td:first-child {    width: 130px;    font-weight: bold;    color: #ff9800;}h2 {    color: #fc6423;}.work {    margin-bottom: 25px;}.work-title {    font-size: 17px;    font-weight: bold;}.work-title a {    margin-left: 5px;    font-size: 14px;    color: #777;}.work-desc {    color: #777;}.work-desc img:first-child {    display: inline;    vertical-align: top;    margin-left: 10px !important;}.post-body img {    display: inline;    vertical-align: top;}.post-body li a {    margin-right: 10px;}</style>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Abozanona, a quiet person, listens to classical music, likes old songs, and addicted to Dota2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Components&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
